# TIM BECK

EMAIL: tim.beck46@gmail.com
LINKEDIN: /in/becktim GITHUB: TimBek2

**SUMMARY** 

Web developer with a passion for smartphones and integration of mundane tasks with technology. I love music and coffee.

SKILLS

Data Analysis, Git, Github, Ruby, Ruby on Raills, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, AJAX, React, React Native, HTML, HTML5, CSS, Juggling, Technology Education, Team Leadership, Problem Solving, Public Speaking, CRM, Business Development, Salesforce.com, SEO, Marketing, Research, Educational Technology, Social Networking, Marketing Communications, Facebook, Social Media, Peer Mediation, Google Analytics, Analytics, Microsoft ACCESS, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Microsoft Office

**PROJECTS** 

#### Next Best Friend

A tinder-style swiping app built using a Rails backend and a React Native front end, drawing data from the PetFinder API to create swipable cards of animals available for adoption with information such as the name, breed, whether the animal has had shots, is spayed/neutered, and a description, as well as contact phone numbers and email addresses if provided. Favorites are saved and buttons on the app pull up native iOS phone and email applications, pulling in the phone number and email addresses from the server data to streamline the process of adopting a new pet.

#### Meteor404

In progress - An app built in Rails using the NASA Meteorite Landings API, the Google Maps Geocoding API, and the Google Maps Directions API. Coordinate and other data for just over 1,000 confirmed but unfound meteorites (meaning no space rock has been found to confirm the exact location of that landing yet) is loaded from the NASA API, converted into an address with the Google Geocoding API, and then directions to that location are generated with the Google Maps Directions API. This app enables you to go find a new meteor, and return a Meteor200!

# **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Dev Bootcamp, Full Stack Developer Training Program

2015 - 2016

Completed a 19-week accelerated training program in Full Stack Development at Dev Bootcamp in NYC. Worked with Ruby and the Sinatra and Rails frameworks to build web applications, as well as front end design built in HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, React, and React Native. Projects included learning React, React Native, and then creating a Tinder-style app for adopting pets in 8 days.

#### Resolution Media SEO Coordinator

2013 - 2014

Managed online marketing analytics platforms like Google Analytics and Adobe SiteCatalyst for clients. Provided technical and content-based recommendations in order to improve overall SEO rankings in targeted specific and high-volume terms. Clients included major pharmaceutical, financial, travel, and entertainment companies.

#### Grovo, Business Development & Community Management Intern

2012 - 2013

Assisted Co-Founders with managing the CRM platform (salesforce.com), data gathering, and organization to assist with everything from identifying sales opportunities to product partners, to helping determine site design and structure for UX decisions. Also assisted original Business Development team as the first community manager, identifying high-engagement users as potential brand champions and building initial relationships with individuals in the PR space.

#### Lend-a-Hand, Inc, Self-Employed

2011 - 2012

Started and ran a single person business for computer and other technology proficiency lessons. Self-promoted with fliers and word of mouth to grow business to over 25 customers. Offered computer lessons for Windows or Mac, iPhone, iPad, and Android devices, and setup, troubleshooting, and IT services for home networks and computers. Created a reputation for high quality service, excellent communication, and patience.

#### Santa Clara University, Law School IT Specialist

2011 - 2011

Provide computer troubleshooting services, as well as repair and hard disk salvaging services to graduates and faculty, often involved ripping the disks from the chassis and using a tool to manually salvage whatever partial data remains on the drive. Needed to balance relationship management with students & faculty while being able to technically troubleshoot and diagnose computers.

### Cadence Chemical Co., Marketing Intern

2009 - 2009

Used data mining techniques and market industry research to identify potential leads for a global chemical sourcing and distribution company, providing things such as base chemicals used in paint. Job responsibilities included utilizing data mining tools to collect large amounts of data regarding factory exhaust fumes and spot patterns or identify potential clients, as well as customer relationship management with business partners in the US and China.

## Cadence Airsoft Co, Co-founder, Vice President of Marketing and Advertisement

2006 - 2008

Successfully entered airsoft market with customization service & retail prices that undercut competition. Used internet boards and Facebook to build a brand and spread reliable information about quality of service and affordability. Identified and established good relations with wholesaler in Hong Kong. Customization services included replacing stock parts with improved versions, or opening and replacing the entire gearbox and wiring of the system.

**EDUCATION** 

#### Santa Clara University - Leavey School of Business

**New Canaan High School**